MORARU **ECATERINA**

PRODUCT DESIGNER

I design large-scale digital products and platforms, enjoying solutions that empower the target user. Having a technical background, I thrive on collaborating with engineering teams while focusing on end-user usability. I have experience involving open-source communities in the development process.

EXPERIENCE

Mar 2022 — Present

Lead Product Designer (CTX) / Analog Devices Leading a team of 8 product designers, that tackles the Continuous Discovery process across multiple initiatives for the "Customer Tools Experience" group.

Oct 2021 — Feb 2022

Senior UX Designer (vLab) / Analog Devices Upgraded Analog's vLab digital evaluation tools' experience.

Sep 2019 — Sep 2021

Lead Product Designer / Arezzo Sky

Designed from scratch the next-gen no-code mobile platform for data processing, together with a team of 25 engineers and another designer.

Nov 2015 — Aug 2019

Lead Interaction Designer / XWiki

Orchestrated the user experience across all XWiki's products. Designed tools and services that bridged the open-source community with the professional enterprise target.

Jan 2014 — Oct 2015

Applications Team Manager / XWiki

Managed a team of 5 developers in assuring a consistent user experience across the 20 most valuable applications selected from over 600 open-source community extensions.

Mar 2009 — Mar 2013

Interaction Designer / XWiki

Designed the collaborative and development features for XWiki, an open-source scalable platform.

valicac@gmail.com +40 (742) 543-821

Iași, Romania www.risherry.ro

EXPERTISE

product-design / interaction-design / product-discovery / prototyping / user-research / user-interviews / accessibility / usability / consistency / experimentation / design-sprint / design-system / design-patterns / standard-compliance / leadership / mentoring / open-source

COMMUNITIES

Feb 2015 — Present

Co-organizer

OpenSourceDesign.net

Growing an international community with over 4000 followers that evanghelizes more open design processes in software development.

May 2008 — Nov 2019

Mentor

Google Summer of Code Introducing hundreds of students from all over the world to opensource software development.

Oct 2007 — Mar 2011

Collaborator Teaching Assistant

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iaşi Pioneered teaching classes of "Human-Computer Interaction" to computer-science students.

EDUCATION

2007 - 2009

M. Sc. Software Engineering

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iaşi

2003 - 2007

B. Sc. Computer Science

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iași



